>> Hello everyone and welcome to
大家好，欢迎来到
the 2021 edition of
2021年版的
the Named Data Networking
命名数据网络
Community meeting that we
社区会议我们希望将是一个很好的机会~!@#$%^&*()
hope will be a good opportunity
希望将是一个很好的机会
to load report on the communities
向社区提交报告
work over the past year and identify
过去一年的工作并识别
new work needed to move
需要进行的新工作
the NDA development and deployment tool.
NDA开发和部署工具。
We have a full two-day agenda
我们有一个为期两天的完整议程安排。
with three panels
与三个小组讨论会
and six presentation sessions.
和六个报告会议。
We have compiled the abstracts
我们已经编纂了摘要
of all talks and panels
的所有演讲和讨论小组会议上
and they are available under
他们可以在下面找到
the Agenda tab on the event page,
活动页面上的议程标签，
as you can see from the screen capture.
如你从屏幕截图中所见。
The theme for this year as you can tell from
今年的主题正如你所能看出来的
the panel names is
会议小组的名称是
Making NDN More Accessible and More Usable.
使NDN更易于访问和使用。
Usability in terms of making life easier for
提高易用性，以便为
NDN application developers by
提高易用性，以便为NDN应用开发者 having a good set of libraries and APIs,
having a good set of libraries and APIs,
拥有一套优良的库和API，
and the accessibility in terms of
和在可访问性方面
making the NDN codebase more
使NDN代码库更加
accessible to everyone who wants
对每个想要的人都更容易访问
to experiment with NDN.
进行NDN实验。
In the presentation sessions,
在演讲环节中，
we have a total of 26 with a mix of
我们总共有26个，混合了
both regular 20-minute presentations
常规的20分钟报告会
and short 10-minute presentations.
和简短的10分钟汇报。
We have a wide spectrum
我们有一个广泛的光谱
of presenters that cover
涵盖了
academic and government research
学术和政府研究
as well as industry with
以及行业内的
presentations from Dell,
戴尔的演示,
Intel, Intelligent Fusion,
英特尔，智能融合，
Pollere, and Siemens.
宝丽来和西门子。
As a community meeting, ideally,
作为一个社区会议，理想情况下，
in addition to sharing progress
除了分享进展情况外，
and identifying open issues,
和识别出悬而未决的问题，
we want to also identify
我们也想要识别出
what the community needs to focus on.
社区需要关注的重点。
In particular, along the line of the theme
特别是沿着这个主题的方向
of usability and
的可用性和
accessibility I just mentioned.
我刚才提到的可用性。
This year, we have as Co-Chairs,
今年，我们的联合主席有，
Marie-Jose Montpetit
今年，我们的联合主席有，Marie-Jose Montpetit 来自康考迪亚大学，
from Concordia University,
来自康考迪亚大学，
and Susmit Shannigrahi
和Susmit Shannigrahi
from Tennessee Tech University.
来自田纳西科技大学。
Marie-Jose, I don't know if you're on,
玛丽-乔泽，我不知道你是否在线，
if you want to say a word.
如果你想说点什么。
>> Yes, I'm on. I can even
是的，我在。我甚至可以
turn my camera for a few seconds.
为几秒钟转动我的摄像头。
>> Okay.
>> 好的。
>> Hello. Yeah,
>> 你好。嗯，
thank you very much for
非常感谢你让我这样做。
allowing me to do this.
允许我这样做。
It's a pleasure and an honor for me to do it.
能够做这件事对我来说是一种快乐和荣幸。
Like you said, and
像你说的那样，还有
Susmit will probably add to this,
苏斯米特可能还会补充这一点，
we wanted to make sure that we
我们想要确保我们
were having a true community meeting.
我们想要确保我们正在举行一个真正的社区会议。
I think we would like
我们想要
everybody to know when you're presenting,
我们想要每个人在你展示的时候都知道，
I think it's not just a presentation,
我认为这不仅仅是一个展示，
it's the start of a dialogue
这是对话的开始。
and I think we made an effort in
我认为我们已经做出了努力在
the panel preparations to
确保我们能够进行对话
between the panelists and between
确保我们能够进行对话, between the panelists and between the community members.
the panelists and the community members.
小组成员和社区成员。
Lofti you mentioned that the theme
Lofti你提到了主题
is to expand the NDN reachability but
是为了扩大NDN的可达性，但是
also to get new people
也是为了吸引新人参与进来
involved and I think you will see
参与其中，我认为你会看到
that there are people in
参与其中的人有些是新来的。
the meeting who are new to this.
会议中有些人是新来的。
I've had a few people saying, Well,
有几个人这么说过，嗯，
we don't know anything about NDN,
我们对NDN一无所知，
but we know a lot about data than
我们对数据了解很多，
data-driven applications and Eve Schuller
数据驱动的应用程序和伊芙·舒勒
from mental told me a few months ago
几个月前从精神上告诉了我
that data is now the fuel of
那些数据现在是
the 21st century so
21世纪如此
everything is data-driven.
一切都是数据驱动的。
We have a large community in NDN
我们在NDN中拥有一个庞大的社区。
that probably has been aware
这可能已经意识到了
of this for quite a long time,
这可能已经意识到了很长一段时间，
so maybe to connect
所以也许是为了连接
all the data-driven people together,
所以也许是为了连接所有以数据为中心的人们，
both inside NDN and outside NDN,
在NDN内部和外部，
we'll just make the community
我们将会让社区
larger and I think we'll profit both.
变得更大，我认为我们双方都会获益。
Susmit, you want to add something?
Susmit，你还有什么要补充的吗？
>> Yes, very briefly.
>> 是的，非常简短。
>> Welcome everyone.
>> 欢迎大家。
I think I'm going
我认为我要去了
to repeat what Lofti and Marie-Jose said.
重复一下洛夫蒂和玛丽-乔丝所说的。
We want this to be a community meeting
我们希望这是一个社区会议。
conference so it's more of
会议，所以它更像是
presenting or lesser presenting
陈述或较少的陈述
what we're doing and more
我们正在做的事情以及更多相关内容
of communicating with the community,
与社区沟通，
what they need and where do you go from here?
他们需要什么以及你接下来要去哪里？
>> Thanks, Marie-Jose and Susmit.
>> 谢谢，Marie-Jose和Susmit。
Finally, for Q&A and discussions,
最后，用于问答和讨论，
let's use the channels primarily,
让我们主要使用频道吧，
we have one for each presentation or
我们为每个演示都准备了一个。
panel as you can see on this list.
我们为每个演示都准备了一个小组，正如你在这个列表上看到的。
You can also unmute your mic and speak
您也可以取消静音并且讲话。
preferably by using the raise hand feature.
最好是使用举手功能。
With that, I think we are on
With that, I think we are on 到此为止，我认为我们已经准备好了。
time to start the first session,
是时候开始第一环节了。
which is on NDN past to
It's time to start the first segment.
present and would be
现在开始并将会是
chaired by Patrick Crowley.
由帕特里克·克劳利主持。
Patrick is a Professor of
帕特里克是一位教授，专攻于
Computer Science and Engineering at
帕特里克是一位教授，专攻于计算机科学与工程，在圣路易斯的华盛顿大学。
the Washington University in St.
圣路易斯的华盛顿大学
Louis and Director of
路易斯和主任
the Applied Research Lab,
应用研究实验室，
which operates multiple testbeds,
它运营着多个测试平台，
including the ONL and the Global NDN testbed.
它运营着多个测试平台，包括ONL和全球NDN测试床。
He was one of the goopy eyes of
他是那些黏糊糊眼睛中的一个
the NSF funded NDN program.
美国国家科学基金会资助的NDN项目。
With that, Patrick,
~,!@#$%^&*()
you want to go ahead, please?
你想先走吗？
>> Thank you, Lofti.
>> 谢谢你，洛夫蒂。
It's wonderful to be
能和你们在一起真是太好了，我期待着
seeing each of you serially as you turn on
看到你们每个人依次打开
your cameras to share
你们的摄像头来分享
with the rest of the NDN community.
与其他NDN社区成员共享。
As Lofti said,
正如Lofti所说，
my name is Patrick Crowley from Washington.
我的名字是Patrick Crowley，来自华盛顿。
I'd like to welcome you to
我想欢迎你来到
the first session of
本届的第一场
this year's NDN community meeting.
今年的NDN社区会议。
Our first session topic for this year is
今年的第一个会议主题是
NDN past to present and the way that
NDN从过去到现在以及它的发展之路
we'll proceed is we
我们将继续的方式是我们
have three speakers in the session,
会议中将有三位发言人，
as you know, I'll
由于您所提供的内容不完整，我无法进行准确的翻译。如果您能提供完整的句子或段落，我将很乐意为您翻译。
introduce each of them before their comments.
在他们发表评论之前，先对每个人进行介绍。
They'll speak for 15 or 16 minutes and then
他们将会发言15到16分钟，然后
we'll have run four minutes
我们将会跑步四分钟。
for questions afterwards.
为了之后提问。
So in good community communication,
所以在良好的社区交流中，
as always,
一如既往地，
we will do our best to get
我们将尽我们最大的努力去
everybody's questions in,
我们将尽我们最大的努力去回答每个人的问题，但时间当然是——
but time is, of course,
一个我们都必须调和的限制。
I will keep my eyes on
我会密切关注
both the Slack channel and
~!@#$%^&*()
also those of you
还有你们这些
who don't have access to Slack.
没有办法使用Slack的你们。
You're welcome, as Lofti said,
洛夫蒂说过，不客气。
to make use of the raise hand feature within
使用举手功能在内
this video conferencing software and you
这个视频会议软件和你~!@#$%^&*()
can ask your own question that way.
你可以用那种方式提出你自己的问题。
Otherwise, I will read the questions that
否则，我将阅读那些问题。
come up in the Slack channel.
出现在Slack频道中。
Without further ado,
毫不犹豫地，
it's my great pleasure to
毫不犹豫地，我很荣幸地向大家
introduce our first speaker.
毫不犹豫地，我很荣幸地向大家介绍我们的第一位演讲嘉宾，Professor Lixia Zhang。
Professor Lixia Zhang from
加州大学洛杉矶分校的计算机科学系的Lixia Zhang教授
the Department of Computer Science in UCLA.
加州大学洛杉矶分校的计算机科学系。
Lixia was the lead PI for
Lixia 是该项目的主要负责人。
the NDN project and
NDN项目和
a tremendous leader and
一位了不起的领导者和
visionary for our community.
一个对我们社区有远见的领袖。
She's going to share with us
她将与我们分享
today lessons learned over the last years.
今天回顾过去几年学到的教训。
Lixia, please take it away.
丽霞，请开始吧。
>> Thank you, Patrick.
>> 谢谢你，帕特里克。
Let me share my screen.
让我分享我的屏幕。
I hope people can see it now.
我希望现在人们能看到了。
.
~!@#$%^&*()
>> I got the task to give a summary.
我得到了做总结的任务。
It's a really overview summary of
这真的是一个非常概括的总结
last year's panel NDN
去年的专家小组NDN
reaching 10-year milestone,
达到了十年的里程碑，
and what we have learned about this 10 years.
达到了十年的里程碑，我们从中学到了什么。
I have to say that the year is really
我不得不说，这一年真的是光阴似箭。
flying by when you're having fun.
时间在快乐中飞逝。
I think the first 10 years
我认为头十年
has passed in no time.
一晃就过去了。
Last year we had the great panel
去年我们有一个很棒的小组讨论会。
chaired by Christian Tschudin.
由Christian Tschudin主持。
Here we should do a summary.
我们应该在这里做一个总结。
We should have did rather after the panel,
我们本应该在小组讨论后再做这件事。
but it's never late though,
但是其实也不算太晚。
let's make it up.
我们来补救吧。
For people who missed the panel,
对于错过小组讨论的人来说，
we can see what we talked to them.
我们可以看看我们和他们讨论了什么。
The panel chair gave us three great topics;
小组主席给了我们三个很好的话题；
what are the highlights of the past 10 years?
过去十年的亮点是什么？
Where things can be
事情可能发生的地方
improved or in other way,
改进了或者以其他方式，
what are the lessons learned,
我们学到了什么教训？
and where we are now?
我们现在在哪里？
That's also lead to
这也导致了
where we should be heading to.
我们应该前往的方向。
Let me just start to talk about,
让我开始谈论，
where the whole thing started?
它是从哪里开始的？
We all know that Van Jacobson gave this talk.
我们都知道Van Jacobson进行了这次演讲。
Now, think about it 15 years back,
现在，回想一下15年前的情景，
looking at the new way
看新的方式
to look at the networking.
看待网络连接。
I remember at
我记得在
the very beginning of this talk,
在这场谈话的一开始，
had made a great analogy.
他做了一个很棒的类比。
He was saying that
他在说~!@#$%^&*()
the Internet is a greater design.
互联网是一个更伟大的设计。
The question is not so much whether
这个问题并不是那么多关于是否
Internet design is bad, but rather,
互联网的设计是否糟糕，而是，
the problems the Internet must
互联网必须解决的问题
solve have changed over time.
随着时间的推移，解决问题的方法也发生了变化。
The main issue is that,
主要问题是，
just like the Kuiper, you can revolution.
就像柯伊伯带一样，你也可以引领革命。
Before that, when people try to understand
在那之前，当人们试图去理解
the planet movement in
星球的运动
the universe with the Earth as the center,
以地球为中心的宇宙，
and the things look complicated to explain.
而事情看起来复杂难以解释。
But the usual one doesn't make a big change,
但通常情况下不会发生大的变化，
say, the center to be under the sun.
说，中心处在阳光之下。
Then overall quickly
那么总体上来说很快。
the picture gets much simpler.
所以，图片变得简单多了。
Therefore, back in 2010,
因此，早在2010年，
we put the best together into a proposal,
我们将最佳方案汇集成一个提案，
creating this bold,
创造这个大胆的，
simple new way to networking.
简单的新型网络方式。
IP just send packets
IP仅仅发送数据包。
from one address to another.
从一个地址发送到另一个地址。
We say that network
我们说网络~!@#$%^&*()
is really about shaping the bags of fits.
确实是关于塑造各种合适的包的。
Counterweight directly address
直接解决配重问题
networking questions
网络问题
by just requesting that name the data.
只需请求那个名字来命名数据。
I remember David Clark mentioned
我记得大卫·克拉克提到过
during that last year panel saying that,
在那最后一年的讨论小组中提到过，
"In the very beginning,
在一开始，
what was exciting about
在一开始，令人兴奋的是
NDN was really its boldness,
NDN的确是它的大胆之处，
its divergence from the current thinking."
它与当前思维的背离。
The natural community tends to
自然界的群落倾向于
focus on the performance of data planes,
专注于数据平面的性能表现，
efficient delivery such and such,
高效的传递等等，
but the NDN is a whole new approach.
但NDN是一种全新的方法。
I think that's really our
我认为那真的是我们的
highlight our number 1.
突出我们的第一位。
They're directly related.
它们是直接相关的。
There's a whole new approach centred on this,
这整个新方法就是围绕这个中心的，
semantically named the secured data.
语义命名了安全数据。
The 10-years experience really told
十年的经验确实说明了这一点。
us that we got the basic idea right.
告诉我们我们已经掌握了基本的正确概念。
The semantically named the secured data
语义命名的安全数据
is a basic building block.
是一个基本的构建模块。
From there, with the word for
是一个基本的构建模块。从那里开始，有了这个词，the applications both people ~!@#$%^&*()
the applications both people
应用程序既服务于人类
had the thought at
也曾有过这样的想法，在
the time as well as the things that only
时间以及那些只有在
got invented after
发明之后
NDN project that got started.
NDN项目已经启动。
The idea is that,
这个想法是，
everything is a bag of
一切都是一袋子~!@#$%^&*()
bits ranging from movies, sports,
从电影、体育赛事，
games, to the IoT sensors,
游戏，到物联网传感器，
to commands, as well as the crypto keys,
到命令，以及加密密钥，
the certificates, and security policies.
证书和安全策略。
Whatever you want, you can issue
无论你想要什么，你都可以发出
the requests to the network and
你的请求发送到网络上，
the network automagically will provide you
网络会自动为你提供
back the correct answer that
网络会自动为你提供正确答案的确认，终端用户可以进行验证。
the end users can verify.
终端用户可以进行验证。
I think semantic naming
我认为是语义命名
reflects application context,
反映了应用上下文，
relations among the network entities,.
网络实体之间的关系，
This lays ground work for
这为...奠定了基础
the content-specific
...laid the foundation for content-specific security solution developments.
security solution developments.
安全解决方案的开发。
Like the trust schema,
像信任模式，
I think that's one of the earlier results
我认为那是项目开始后不久的早期成果之一。
few years after the project started.
项目开始后的几年。
It's representing I think
它代表了我认为的。
a brand new breakthrough I'd say,
一个全新的突破，我会说，
is addressing
正在解决
this fountain
这个喷泉
security challenges facing us today.
我们今天面临的安全挑战。
Now, starting from
现在，从
the semantically named the secured data,
将数据命名为安全数据，
we'll apply the concept
我们将应用这个概念
to many different problems.
到许多不同的问题。
Internet of Things, as I mentioned,
物联网，正如我所提到的，
those require networking,
那些需要联网，
that requires delayed tolerant support.
需要延迟容忍支持。
The distributors social apps that the Memphis
孟菲斯的分销商社交应用程序
demonstrated at the ICA in 2019.
在2019年的ICA上展示。
There's a disruption, tolerant to networking.
存在一种对网络中断具有容忍性的技术。
I think that after researchers
我认为研究人员在这个方向上进行了探索，并创造了那个。
explored in this direction and created that.
在这个方向上进行了探索，并创造了那个。
More recently, we have
最近，我们已经在这个方向上进行了探索，并创造了那个，seen satellite networking looking~!@#$%^&*()
seen satellite networking looking
卫星网络观察
to the application Endian
应用于Endian
to address their problems,
解决他们的问题，
because Endian really provide
因为Endian确实提供了
that built-in delay tolerance support
内置的延迟容忍支持
in as well as Edge computing.
以及边缘计算。
Highlight 3. We can have great ideas,
我们可以有伟大的想法，
but without NSF support
但没有国家科学基金会的支持
the great ideas wouldn't have come very far.
伟大的想法不会走得很远。
I think the whole team appreciated really
我认为整个团队都非常感激。
the unfailing support from
持续不断的支持来自
NSF and also from the global community.
来自国家科学基金会以及全球社区的支持。
That was started in 2010.
那是在2010年开始的。
I must say talk
我必须说话
about the lessons learnt next step.
关于学到的教训和下一步的计划。
I didn't know at
我当时不知道
the time what that sent out to do,
~!@#$%^&*()
but I figured the FAA program was serious,
但我觉得联邦航空管理局的项目是严肃的，
we got it down by the end of three years.
我们在三年的末尾解决了这个问题。
The time has told us how around we are.
时间告诉了我们我们是多么地团结。
But nevertheless, there's continued support
但尽管如此，支持仍在持续。
and encouragement from NSF,
和来自美国国家科学基金会的支持与鼓励，
and as a result,
因此，
as you can see in the next two days,
在接下来的两天里，你可以看到，
there's a great new directions
在接下来的两天里，你可以看到，有一些很棒的新方向，pushing the frontier for~!@#$%^&*()
pushing the frontier for
推动前沿发展，为了
networking and addressing
网络和寻址
the burning issues that's
这些迫切需要解决的问题
persisted in the Internet for many years.
在互联网上持续了许多年。
We really got a dedicated
我们真的有一个敬业
and persistent team.
我们真的有一个敬业和持之以恒的团队。
I look at the session chairs
我看向了会议主席。
for this year's Endian.com.
今年的Endian.com。
We can see that a majority of
我们可以看到大多数
the Endian PAs,
Endian PAs 结束了。
the teams started in 2010,
团队从2010年开始，
who are still here are pushing,
仍在这里的人正在推动，
continue to push this exciting direction.
继续推动这个令人兴奋的方向。
There's a broader community as you can see
在您所看到的，有一个更广泛的社区。
from the presentation in the next two days.
在接下来的两天里的报告中。
Lessons. I just want to convey a few ideas.
在接下来的两天里的报告中，我只想传达几个观点。
This talk does not reflect
这次演讲并不反映
the panel's shared understanding,
本次演讲并不反映小组的共识，但这确实是个人观点。
but this really personal view.
但这确实是个人观点。
I hope I'm going go to round.
我希望我能走到最后。
I think the Endian project
我认为Endian项目
started with the FAA charging all there.
开始时，美国联邦航空管理局对所有人收费。
We need to divide
我们需要分开
the new Internet architecture.
新的互联网架构。
The starting point at
起点在
the very beginning were focused
起点在专注于
on that how we support Internet at scale.
在我们如何支持大规模互联网方面。
But think about it.
但想想看。
We have been doing networking using
我们一直在使用网络技术进行联络
hydrolysis from back then,
从那时起的水解反应，
already 30 plus years.
已经超过30年了。
This idea of naming data
这个命名数据的想法
and the stateful forwarding were just as
和有状态转发一样
two novel concept and
两个新颖的概念和
the team gets bombarded
团队遭到了猛烈的轰炸
with all the questions.
面对所有这些问题。
How can such approaches possibly scale?
这些方法如何可能扩展呢？
Rather than the question to say what you can
与其问你能用这些全新概念做什么？
do with this brand new concepts?
你能用这些全新概念做什么？
We really spend the last few years
我们确实花了最近几年的时间
after they focus on the problems.
在他们专注于这些问题之后。
Those are important questions,
这些是重要的问题，
but not the first order burning questions.
但不是最紧迫的问题。
Would you leave the world
你会离开这个世界吗？
a better understanding of
更好的理解
how to do a new architecture?
如何设计一种新的架构？
Architecture solves application problems,
架构解决应用问题，
not network forward problems.
解决网络前进问题。
Therefore it really
因此它确实
requires an overall picture.
需要一个整体的画面。
If one solely focused on how network
如果一个人只专注于网络如何
can efficiently forwarding pay kits,
能高效转发支付套件，
just the other network layer.
仅仅是另一个网络层。
You would never gets to
你永远不会得到
departing from the existing IP model.
离开现有的IP模型。
That's really my insight, get out of it.
这确实是我的深刻见解，走出这个困境。
The new architecture really
确实是新的架构
start from edges,
从边缘开始，
even as IP when
即使作为IP的时候
both NIST has changed over the years.
NIST 随着时间的推移已经发生了变化。
IP started from the edge
IP起源于边缘
by addressing the burning issues.
通过解决紧迫问题。
How we can build a
我们如何能够构建一个
resilient communication system out
我们如何能够构建一个有韧性的通信系统，确保这种最大努力交付。
of this best effort delivery
的这种最大努力交付
of datagrams from anywhere to anywhere.
的数据报从任何地方发送到任何地方。
For Endian to really
为了让Endian真正实现~!@#$%^&*()
launching a new architecture evolution,
启动一项新的架构演变，
we need to start from the edge
我们需要从边缘开始
and not the infrastructure.
我们不应该从基础设施开始。
I remember back in the
我记得回到在
2017 when we had the SITCOM hosted at UCLA,
2017年我们在加州大学洛杉矶分校举办了SITCOM，
we had informal PI meeting
我们举行了非正式的项目负责人会议
and we already made it
我们已经做到了。
very clear that direction
方向非常清晰
of Endian will be edging.
Endian的边缘将会被切割。
Lesson number 2. We really from
第2课。我们真的从
last year how we
去年我们如何
look back and understand our own limitations.
回顾并理解我们自己的局限性。
Van whose always sharp look
Van whose always sharp look ~!@#$%^&*()
into the problems to the facts.
深入问题，探究事实。
I remember his comment
我记得他的评论。
that seems that a lot of
这似乎是很多
the research is done in
研究是在~!@#$%^&*()
the researchers' comforts zone.
研究人员的舒适区。
I think this statement is
我认为这个说法是
a little over shooting,
有些过头了，
but I can see that there
但我可以看出那里
is a problem, he pointed out.
是一个问题，他指出。
I think there's a layer to
我认为还有一层
Internet architecture somehow
互联网架构在某种程度上
seemed to how segregated
似乎是如何被隔离开来的
not only the functional modules,
不仅是功能模块，
but also the research community
但也包括研究界
and the peoples to expertise.
和各方面的专家。
I would admits that the majority of
我必须承认大多数情况下
NDN *** came with
~!@#$%^&*()
a network background and therefore,
我们因此拥有网络背景，
we don't have the intact understanding
我们没有完整的理解。
of what are the burning issues
我们没有完整的理解。关于什么是迫切的问题，that applications must dissolve.
that applications must dissolve.
应用程序必须解散。
We are still unfortunately how
我们仍然很不幸地如何
Professor Jeff Burke,
杰夫·伯克教授，
who came from the application area.
他来自应用领域。
I think he provided
我认为他提供了
a tremendous and invaluable input,
他提供了巨大而宝贵的输入，
still the research going towards
仍然有研究在朝着这些问题的解决方向进行。
the direction of addressing these problems.
解决这些问题的方向。
I think that these 10 years
我认为这十年
of training is really the place of
培训真的是...的地方
training to make one
...的地方，能够看到大局并成为
to see the big picture and to become
能够看到大局并成为
a journalist instead of
能够看到大局并成为一名记者而不是专家的
a specialist with
一名专家具有
a narrative focused research agenda.
以叙事为中心的研究议程。
How to develop the architecture?
如何发展架构？
I think gradually over time,
我认为随着时间的推移，
we actually saw that more clearly
我们实际上看得更清楚了。
that ultimately the goal for
最终的目标是
the networking is to enable applications.
网络的目的是为了支持应用程序。
Then we actually putting into
然后我们实际上正在投入
annual report as saying
年度报告中提到
that we really need to
我们确实需要
move towards this application
朝着这个应用程序前进
driven architecture development.
驱动架构开发。
Because solving real problems will force
因为解决实际问题会迫使
all the specifics on
解决具体细节上的问题
the table and you had to fill in the details.
您需要填写详细信息的表格。
The more importantly,
更重要的是，
we're here help us verify and validate
我们在这里帮助我们验证和确认。
whether this architecture design
是否这个架构设计没有朝着正确的方向发展。
isn't moving towards the right direction.
没有朝着正确的方向发展。
I think in the more recent years,
我认为在近几年来，
in particular last year,
特别是去年，
the focus has been moving
重点已经转移
towards building usable applications.
朝着构建可用应用程序的方向发展。
That tracked the application developers
跟踪应用程序开发者的动态。
[inaudible].
~!@#$%^&*()
As you can see from the next two days,
从接下来的两天你可以看出来，
there's a major focus
在接下来的两天你可以看出来，有一个主要焦点是关于构建高级APIs，
about building high level APIs,
关于构建高级APIs，
usable security, and the plug and play so
可用安全性，以及即插即用功能，以便我们共同解决问题。
that we both solve the problems.
我们共同解决问题。
We also opens the door to
我们还打开了大门以
engage the large community,
吸引了广大群众，
regarding where we are now.
关于我们现在所处的位置。
Let me take it quick,
让我快点处理。
I'm running out of time.
我快没时间了。
I think that people should understand.
我认为人们应该理解。
Developing architecture takes time.
发展建筑需要时间。
The Internet may look
互联网可能看起来
like an overnight success.
像一夜成名的成功。
But I want to point it out that
但我想指出的是
the Internet [inaudible] that started
互联网[听不清]开始
in the early '70s
在20世纪70年代初
is actually it takes about 20 years,
实际上它大约需要20年，
when the white just formed.
在白色刚刚形成的时候。
But it took the previous 20 years to
但这之前花了20年时间才
finalize the architecture
确定架构
to mature the implementation.
使实施成熟。
Between the '81 to the '90s.
从1981年到1990年代。
Ten plus years where a number of issues
十多年来，许多问题
was identified and fixed in [inaudible],
被识别并在[听不清]中修复了，
PGP got I did.
我得到了PGP。
Congestion can show into
拥堵可能会表现为~!@#$%^&*()
a real problem and get
一个真正的问题并且得到
the soft and a number of other issues.
解决了这个软件和其他许多问题。
the beginning of that long.
我们现在所处的，那个漫长的开始。
The only other process that we have learned.
我们所学到的唯一其他过程。
What are the most difficult
What are the most difficult ~!@#$%^&*()
things to push out
最难推动的事情
NDN and we learnt about how to get there.
NDN，我们学习了如何到达那里。
That is edge-in.
这是边缘进入。
Here what I mean is that,
这就是我的意思是，
you really need to develop
你真的需要发展
the solutions and try it
尝试这些解决方案
out at the edges
在边缘处
like supporting edge computing.
像支持边缘计算。
As well as we develop
以及我们开发
for applications that can't
对于不能够
really run over anything, any connectivity.
真的可以覆盖任何东西，任何连接。
That we can test the architecture to see
我们可以测试这个架构来查看
this architecture is doing
我们可以测试这个架构来查看这个架构在做什么，以及什么是正确的事情，还有什么可能是
the right thing and what's maybe
正确的事情以及可能的事情
missing we could add it up.
我们可以把它加起来。
This is my last slide.
这是我的最后一张幻灯片。
I just want to say that
我只想说
this is a community meeting.
这是一个社区会议。
Lots of you already talked.
你们很多人已经发言了。
In the next two days,
在接下来的两天里，
we're really looking to
我们真的很希望能够
a sharing
共享
all the achievements over the years,
多年来的所有成就，
identify the new issues,
识别新问题，
and then collecting input to formulate to
然后收集输入以制定解决方案
the marching order for
为了即将到来的一年
the coming year. Thank you very much.
即将到来的一年。非常感谢您。
>> Made sure your timing
确保了你的时机
is extraordinary. Well done.
是非凡的。做得好。
I've got one question has come in via chat.
我收到了一个通过聊天发来的问题。
Others, please do.
其他人，请做。
Hope we can spend our next few minutes
希望我们能花接下来的几分钟时间
here picking leashes brain productively.
在这里富有成效地挑选束缚的思维产品。
One question for you via
一个问题要问你通过
chat here from Kumar.
库马尔发来的聊天信息。
What is the scale of NDN?
NDN的规模是多少？
Interested in how you
~!@#$%^&*()
interpret that question?
理解那个问题？
>> That's a great question.
这是一个很好的问题。
This actually, I didn't have time to
实际上，我没有时间去
elaborate on this last year.
实际上，我没有时间去详细阐述这个问题去年。这是一个根本性问题。
This is a fundamental question.
这是一个根本性问题。
It's NDN just a, not really our problems.
这是NDN的问题，不真正是我们的问题。
I think that that's related question.
我认为那是相关的问题。
That's reading the scale.
这是在读数刻度。
I think NDN fundamentally
我认为NDN从根本上来说
provides a way to look
提供了一种观察方式
at how to build network
提供了一种观察方式，如何构建网络，the systems, starting from application.
the systems, starting from application.
系统，从应用开始。
Because like I said,
因为就像我说的，
I kept using the informal words,
我一直在使用非正式用语，
application is a goal.
应用是一个目标。
What we do is to
我们所做的是为了
provide what applications needed.
提供所需的应用程序。
Therefore, I can think of NDN
因此，我可以考虑NDN
as a way to solve [inaudible] and
作为解决[听不清]和
ethical problems without
伦理问题而不是
a clear understanding of application needs,
对应用需求的清晰理解，
you will never solve the real problem.
你永远无法解决真正的问题。
The simple example would be,
简单的例子可能是，
IP side the point of delivery.
IP侧的交付点。
But hides the Internet is
但隐藏了互联网是
still only do point-to-point delivery.
仍然只进行点对点的递送。
It already mattered down years back.
它已经在几年前就变得重要了。
Today what we do is we're pass
今天我们所做的是我们正在传递。
this multicast equivalent dissemination,
这种多播等效传播，
but not at the network layer because
但不是在网络层，因为
IT has not changed.
IT没有改变。
But it is a CDN companies
但它是一家CDN公司。
provided at the function,
提供在功能层面上，
at the application layer through all kinds of
在应用层通过各种在功能层面上，技巧和作弊在架构上。
tricks and cheats on the architecture.
技巧和作弊在架构上。
Understanding what to correct
理解应该纠正什么
the building block,
建筑积木，
we can lead to alter the future with
我们可以引导着改变未来，借助
this simple architecture and
这个简单的架构和
with the security built in.
带有内置的安全功能。
>> Good. In the last couple of minutes,
在过去的几分钟里，
here a pair of
在过去的几分钟里，这里一对儿
questions have come in which all
在过去的几分钟里，这里一对儿问题已经提出，所有这些问题都会合成你认为需要的东西吗？
synthesizes what do you think is needed?
合成了你认为需要的东西吗？
The first question is what do
第一个问题是什么
you think is needed for
您认为需要什么来
wider adoption in commercial
广泛应用于商业领域
and sort of application domains?
Widely used in commercial fields, that's the first and then the second are, ~!@#$%^&*()
That's the first and then the second are,
这是第一个，然后第二个是，
what are your thoughts about
你对此有什么看法？
or what are your pointers
对此你有什么指点？
for important near chart
对此你有什么指点？for important near chart research directions should be tackled next?
research directions should be tackled next?
接下来应该着手解决哪些研究方向？
>> Let me answer the second question first,
>> 让我先回答第二个问题，
because we are working
因为我们正在工作
on collecting those pointers.
在收集那些要点。
This not there yet.
这还没到那个地步。
But as soon as we get ready,
但是一旦我们准备好了，
we'll sent to the community.
我们会发送给社区。
We're thinking about global community.
我们在考虑全球社区。
We need to first collect a set of
我们首先需要收集一套
educational pointers for people to
教育性的指导意见给人们
learn about NDN and
了解NDN和
the tutorials to the code base and
代码库的教程和
the problems for people
人们遇到的问题
interested to
对...感兴趣
contribute to the solution development.
为解决方案的开发做出贡献。
As for the first one.
至于第一个。
Let me just state in the early days,
让我说一下，在早期，
the focus was on the natural level and that,
重点放在了自然水平上，以及这一点，
all this competition,
所有这些竞争，
there's attempted to trick to
尝试去使用诡计来
the architecture to see how it can change
尝试去使用诡计来改变NDN架构的设计。
the NDN architecture as a design.
尝试将NDN架构作为一种设计。
I mean the NDN architecture
我指的是NDN架构。
to make the NDN router run fast.
为了让NDN路由器运行得更快。
I think that is not the right direction.
我认为那不是正确的方向。
NDN router needs to run fast.
NDN路由器需要运行得快。
Nevertheless, if we thought
尽管如此，如果我们认为
the applications produce traffic,
应用程序产生流量，
there's no point to build
建造它是没有意义的
terabytes NDN routers
太字节NDN路由器
The fundamental thing is,
基础的事情是，
I said, networking is to enable applications.
我说过，网络是为了使应用程序能够运行。
Applications have problems today,
如今，应用程序面临着问题，
to really scale,
要真正扩展规模，
to secure, and more importantly.
要确保，更重要的是。
I hope in actually trying to
我希望在实际尝试去
encouraging my former students to
鼓励我以前的学生去
start house in the area of
开始在该地区的房子
developing the age in applications.
发展应用程序的时代。
You can develop a smart home applications.
你可以开发智能家居应用程序。
That's not shipping all your home secret,
这并不意味着要泄露你家的所有秘密。
like my conversation with my husband.
像我和我丈夫的对话。
Oh, God. To the home devices into the car.
哦，天哪。把家里的设备搬到车里。
The secure applications.
安全的应用程序。
Then we don't know how to argue and
那我们就不知道如何争辩了，
about how Amazon or Google,
关于亚马逊或谷歌，
while they might say considerations.
他们可能会说是出于考虑。
If you didn't put your data
如果你没有把你的数据
into the Clouds in the first place,
备份到云端的话，
if you need that,
如果你需要那个，
use the Clouds for archiving,
使用云服务进行存档，
you sent the encrypted data.
你发送了加密数据。
I think that we can step factor level,
我认为我们可以提升因素级别，
look at a lot
看很多
of effort that's going on today.
正在进行的努力。
Let's aims at amending
让我们旨在修正
the shortcomings of the existing
现有的不足之处
[BACKGROUND] solutions instead of dividing
[背景] 解决方案而不是分割
a solution from the first principle
从第一原理出发的解决方案
to just eliminate those problems.
就是为了消除这些问题。
Again, when we build up to this,
我们再次建立起这个的时候，
not only we should
我们不仅应该
list the short-term project,
列出短期项目，
we probably can also list our guesses,
我们可能还可以列出我们的猜测，
what may be the urgent needs
可能是紧迫的需求
for the product in
为了产品在
the market that people can try.
市场上人们可以尝试的。
>> That's great, Alicia.
>> 太棒了，Alicia。
Thank you and I think we'll continue to
谢谢，我认为我们将继续
revisit some of your thoughts here.
重新审视你的一些想法。
Progress to the next two days.
在接下来的两天里取得进展。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
>> Time is sadly running right along.
时间不幸地在飞速流逝。
Next up in session one is
接下来是第一场的下一位演讲者
Professor Beichuan Zhang from
来自计算机科学系的张北川教授
the Department of Computer Science
计算机科学系
at the University of Arizona.
在亚利桑那大学。
I'm going to keep my [NOISE] introduction
我将保持我的介绍简短，以便我们能够
brief so that we can
尽量简短以便我们能够
maximize the time given to the speakers.
尽量增加给演讲者的时间。
He'll giving us an overview
他将给我们一个概览。
of the NDM codebase.
的NDM代码库。
Hopefully Beichuan, you
的NDM代码库。Hopefully Beichuan, you can turn on your camera and start
can turn on your camera and start
可以打开你的摄像头并开始
sharing your slides. Welcome, Beichuan.
分享你的幻灯片。欢迎，Beichuan。
>> Patrick, can you see my slides?
>> 帕特里克，你能看到我的幻灯片吗？
>> Yes, indeed, we can see them just fine.
>> 是的，确实，我们可以很清楚地看到它们。
>> Great. Thank you, Patrick.
>> 太好了。谢谢你，帕特里克。
It's great to be here part
很高兴能来到这里。
of the NDN come to discuss how
来讨论如何的NDN
to move forward NDN
向前发展NDN
and the overall pricing based architecture.
和整体的定价基础架构。
My job in this talk is to
我的任务在这个讲话中是要
give a overview of the code development.
提供代码开发的概览。
However, over the past 10 years,
然而，在过去的10年里，
the original NDN product team and
原始的NDN产品团队以及
also the general NDN IC and
同时还有整个NDN IC和
community has developed so much codebase
社区已经开发了如此庞大的代码库。
and so many software.
和如此多的软件。
It's impossible to cover everything.
要想面面俱到是不可能的。
Also, I don't think
也，我不认为
that's the purpose of people
这就是人们的目的。
coming to this community meeting.
来参加这个社区会议。
Rather than doing a comprehensive coverage,
相比于进行全面的报道，
I want to give a quick overview of
我想快速概述一下
some major basic NDN
一些主要的基础NDN(命名数据网络)
software development effort and
软件开发工作和
then recurse on recent progress
然后递归处理最近的进展情况。
and the status of those.
以及那些的状态。
But really the main intention is to set up
但其实主要意图是为了建立
the background for the next two days
未来两天的背景情景
when we discuss how to improve the process,
当我们讨论如何改进流程时，
how to improve the overall software
如何改善整体软件
and the development effort.
和开发工作量。
The first thing is the forwarding daemon,
第一件事是转发守护进程，
the NDN forwarding daemon we call it an FD.
我们称之为FD的NDN转发守护进程。
That's probably
这可能是
the oldest software we developed.
这可能是我们开发的最古老的软件。
The intention is to be
意图是要成为
a reference implementation of
参考实现
the basic NDN functionality.
基本的NDN功能。
It's C++ implementation.
它是C++实现的。
It has all the basic
它具备所有基本的
NDN packet forwarding mechanism,
NDN数据包转发机制，
has a contents store for caching,
具有用于缓存的内容存储，
pending interest table,
待处理利息表，
and the forwarding table.
和转发表。
Currently we support
目前我们支持
multiple forwarding strategies.
我们支持多种转发策略。
For example, there's
例如，有
multicast forwarding strategy that
多播转发策略是指
an income interests can go to
一个收入可以增长
multiple next hop at same time.
多个下一跳同时进行。
We have the so-called best router strategy,
我们有所谓的最佳路由器策略，
which will foward interests to
它将会将兴趣转发至
the best next-hop that is the current moment.
它将会选择在当前时刻最佳的下一跳。
But if that next hop doesn't work or
但如果那个下一跳不起作用或者
doesn't work well, yeah,
不起作用，是的，
if that next hop doesn't bring data back,
如果下一个跳点没有带回数据，
then the strategy will
那么策略将会
forward the next interests
转发下一个兴趣。
to the second best next hop.
转发到第二优先的下一个跳点。
We also have the so-called ASF strategy.
我们还有所谓的ASF策略。
That strategy will proactively prove
这个策略将主动证明
some other next hops and
一些其他的下一跳路由
choose whichever give the data
选择提供数据的那个选项。
back earliest and we'll use that one.
选择最早的那个，我们会使用那个。
There's also interface to add new strategies.
还有一个添加新策略的接口。
One intention of the design is
设计的一个意图是
to make it modular so that
使其模块化，以便
researchers can plug in their own strategies
研究人员可以插入他们自己的策略
and other improvement of the code.
以及其他代码的改进。
Also, in the same spirit,
同样的，本着相同的精神，
the NFD to applications
我们将NFD的内部细节暴露给应用程序通过NFD管理协议。
through NFD Management Protocol,
通过NFD管理协议，
which communicated between the application
通过应用程序之间的通信，
and NFD itself,
和NFD本身，
yielding interests and data.
产生利息和数据。
This way you can configure and
这样你就可以配置和
control the forwarding daemon.
控制转发守护进程。
The NFD runs on multiple platforms.
NFD在多个平台上运行。
We actively maintain its Android version.
我们积极维护其安卓版本。
Try to keep up with the main release of NFD.
努力跟上NFD的主要发布版本。
We also successfully run it on
我们也成功地在其他平台上运行了它
some other platform such
我们也成功地在其他一些平台上运行了它，比如用于家用路由器的WRT，
as WRT for the home router,
作为家用路由器的WRT，
Raspberry Pi and some others.
树莓派和其他一些设备。
But some of these
但这些中的一些
are actively maintained by individuals,
被个人积极维护着，
but some of them are not actively maintained.
但其中一些并没有得到积极维护。
But in general, I believe
但总的来说，我相信
it's not much effort
这不费多少力气
to pull this to a similar platform.
将这个迁移到一个类似的平台上。
NFD right now runs on
将NFD目前运行在~!@#$%^&*()
the NDN testbed maintained by Zhenkai Zhu.
NFD当前运行在由Zhenkai Zhu维护的NDN测试环境中。
This testbed I was
这个测试环境我是
about 30 plus knows globally
大约有30多人在全球范围内知道这件事。
and activity running this NFD
大约有30多人在全球范围内知道这件事，并且默认策略是ASF。并且活动执行这个NFD。
and the default strategy is ASF.
并且默认策略是ASF。
If you do an experiment on the NDN testbed,
如果你在NDN测试床上进行实验，
this will be the forwarding beam
这将是转发的数据流。
and you're going to use underlie.
你将会使用基础设施。
The NDN tools is
一套基本的NDN应用程序包。
If you're a new user and you try NFD,
如果你是新用户并且尝试使用NFD，
you probably will also get this NDN tools,
你可能还会得到这些NDN工具，
so that you can run
以便你能够运行
the application on top of it and test it.
应用程序并对其进行测试。
NDN tools including tools such
NDN工具，包括此类工具，
as silver file,
作为银色文件，
retriever file, you can log the traffic.
作为检索文件，你可以记录流量。
You can have the packet dissector
你可以使用数据包解析器
to read the log
来读取日志
and some simple tools
和一些简单的工具
to help use and tell the software.
为了帮助使用和告知软件。
We keep actively developing an ID
我们持续积极地开发一个身份识别系统，
and a new release is
和一个新版本即将发布
probably going to happen very soon.
可能很快就会发生。
In this new release,
在这个新版本中，
you're going to see we completed
在这个新版本中，我们已经完成了
the transition to packet format Version 0.3,
在这个新版本中，我们已经完成了过渡到数据包格式版本0.3，
which has a bunch
这包含了许多
of changes to the packet format.
的数据包格式变更。
I'd actually hide some highlights.
我其实会隐藏一些重点。
There's new signed interests format.
有新的签署利益格式。
Most interests, they are not signed,
大多数利益是不需要签署的，
but optionally you can sign the interests.
但你可以选择性地签署这些利益。
For example, if actually
例如，如果实际上
carries the command that what device,
执行命令的是哪个设备，
you'll want to sign that interests.
你会想要签署那份利益相关文件。
That format for
那种格式用于
the assigned interests got updated.
指定的利益得到了更新。
We also have updated some naming conventions.
我们还更新了一些命名规则。
For example, if a particular name component
例如，如果一个特定的名字成分
has some special meaning,
具有某种特殊含义，
rather than using some code,
而不是使用某种代码，
we say here is the type,
我们在这里所说的是类型，
you can type the component of
您可以输入组件的~!@#$%^&*()
a name so that it more,
一个名称，以便它更加，
consistent across the usage of
一致地使用在
this special name components.
这些特殊的名字组成部分。
Also in this release,
同样在这个版本中，
we draw up to the support
我们提供了支持。
of most of the selectors.
大多数选择器。
If people don't know what's selectors are,
如果人们不知道什么是选择器，
those are tutors on
那些是导师在我们进行名称和数据匹配时。
when we do the name and data matching.
当我们进行名称和数据匹配时。
In addition to include
除了包括
names and your interests,
姓名和你的兴趣爱好，
you can also include some selectors to limit
您还可以包括一些选择器来限制
which data might satisfy that interests.
哪些数据可能满足那些兴趣。
We find that most of
我们发现大多数
selectors are either rarely
选择器要么很少使用，要么会引起
used or cause
使用或引起
significant problem to the performance.
对性能造成了重大问题。
We have found the alternatives
我们已经找到了替代方案。
to achieve those functionality.
为了实现那些功能。
Therefore, we
为了实现那些功能，因此我们放弃了对选择器的支持。
dropped the support of the selectors.
我们放弃了对选择器的支持。
We added support of hop limit
我们增加了跳数限制的支持。
so you can lead me to the worst-case.
所以你可以引导我了解最坏的情况。
How long a packet can live in the network.
数据包在网络中可以存活多长时间。
A new feature that's going to be included in
即将包含在内的一个新功能是
this release is so-called async behavior.
这个版本被称为异步行为。
What happens is if there
如果那里有什么发生的话，
are new interests coming into the NRD
新的兴趣是否正在涌入NRD
and there's no cache data
并且没有缓存数据
and there's no routing entry
并且没有路由条目
to forward that interest.
转发那个兴趣。
Previously, NRD will drop
此前，NRD会下降
those interests because it
不知道如何处理这些利益，因为它
doesn't know what to do with those interests.
不知道如何处理这些利益。
But in some applications,
但在某些应用中，
they send interests before
他们之前发送了兴趣。
the data was actually generated
数据实际上是生成的
or even before
或甚至在此之前
the routing prefix was announced.
路由前缀已宣布。
But we want to
但我们想要
accommodate this use scenario so
适应这种使用场景，所以
that the data retrieval
为了适应这种使用场景，所以数据检索可以异步发生，
can happen asynchronously,
可以异步发生，
meaning the consumer and
意味着消费者和
the producer don't have
制片人没有
to be online at the same time.
制片人可以同时在线。
The producer can put data at
制片人可以放置数据在
one time and consumer can retrieve data
一次性，消费者可以检索数据
at another time and either event
在另一个时间，无论哪种情况发生
can happen earlier or later.
可能会提前或延后发生。
To support that, NRD has to buffer
为了支持这一点，NRD需要进行缓冲。
the new interest so that
为了支持这一新兴的兴趣，以便
don't have any forwarding entry yet.
尚未有任何转发条目。
Interests coming in, no data,
没有数据传入，
no forwarding entry, and
没有转发条目，而且
nothing will buffer those interests.
没有什么能缓冲那些利益。
At a later time,
在稍后的时间里，
if forwarding entry shows up, for example,
如果出现转发条目，例如，
the producer shows up or
制作人出现或者
a data prefix got announced then
宣布了一个数据前缀后
the NRD will look at those buffered interests
NRD将会查看那些缓冲的利益。
and send them out
并将它们发送出去。
according to this forwarding entry.
根据此转发条目。
>> Beichuan.
>> 北川。
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> I'm very sorry to interrupt.
>> 我很抱歉打扰了。
I just wanted to let you know we're
我只是想告诉你我们即将~!@#$%^&*()
going to need to start taking
即将需要开始进行
questions in about two minutes
即将需要开始进行问题环节, 大约两分钟后。
if that won't affect you.
如果那不会影响你。
I know time is flying. [OVERLAPPING]
我知道时间在飞逝。[同时发生]
>> I'm sorry.
>> 对不起。
I think I've lost track of the time.
我想我已经忘记了时间。
We have revision of NFD Developer's Guide.
我们有NFD开发者指南的修订版。
There are other NRD forwarders.
还有其他的NRD转发器。
NDN-DPDK you're going to hear it later today
您稍后会听到关于NDN-DPDK的介绍。
is focused on high performance.
侧重于高性能。
YaNFD focus on simplified design
YaNFD专注于简化设计
of the forwarder compared to NFD.
与NFD相比，转发器的性能。
NDN-Lite is a forwarder
NDN-Lite是一个转发器
focused on embedded
专注于嵌入式
and constrained environments.
和受限环境。
Although the whole package
尽管整个包裹
is much more than a forwarder,
它不仅仅是一个转发器，
it has other libraries
它还有其他的库。
to support applications.
以支持应用程序。
Besides the forwarders,
除了转发器，
we also have a number of
我们还有许多
libraries to support
我们还有许多库来支持不同语言的绑定。
different language bindings.
支持不同语言的绑定。
These libraries are actually
这些库实际上是
used in developing applications.
用于开发应用程序。
We have the sync protocols,
我们有同步协议，
which is basically
它基本上是
the transport protocol equivalent in NDN.
它在NDN中相当于传输协议。
It synchronize selected namespace
它同步选定的命名空间。
and data among multiple participants.
和数据在多个参与者之间进行同步。
They may start with different state of
他们可能从不同的状态开始
how much data they
他们有多少数据
have and then after running a Sync,
在运行同步之后，
they all synchronize with each other
它们都彼此同步。
about the namespace
关于命名空间
of data they want to sync.
他们想要同步的数据类型。
There are different designs of
有不同的设计
how to do this.
如何做这个。
Mostly different from how
大多与如何不同
they represent the states
它们代表着各种状态
and communicate and synchronize.
并进行通信和同步。
PSync use Bloom Filter
PSync使用布隆过滤器。
and Invertible Bloom Filter.
和可逆布隆过滤器。
StateVectorSync use
StateVectorSync使用
a state vector to represent states.
一个状态向量来表示状态。
Both of them are actually being
两者实际上都在积极开发中。
actively developed.
积极开发中。
NDNCERT and Repo.
NDNCERT和Repo。
The cert is to automate
证书是用来自动化的
the managed retrieval and management
管理的检索和管理
of NDN certificates to facilitate
NDN证书的便利化处理
all the security operations.
所有的安全操作。
Repo manage the data repository
管理数据仓库
so that you can solve
以便你能解决
data without
数据没有
having the original data producer
拥有原始数据生产者
to be online all the time.
随时在线。
We have evaluation platforms in
我们有评估平台在~!@#$%^&*()
different level and different tools.
不同层次，不同工具。
NdnSIM is a simulator.
NdnSIM 是一个模拟器。
The mini-NDN virtualized emulator
迷你-NDN虚拟化仿真器
that you can run the real NRD
您可以运行真实的NRD
and other NDN software.
和其他NDN软件。
NDN Testbed, as I mentioned,
NDN Testbed，正如我所提到的，
is global testbed with
是一个全球性的测试平台，
30 plus nodes and they run
30多个节点正在运行
NLSR as routing protocol
NLSR作为路由协议
and as a forwarding strategy.
作为转发策略。
People have been using the testbed
人们一直在使用测试平台
to do various experiments.
进行各种实验。
I think the next step we need to
我认为我们需要迈出的下一步是
focus on accessibility, usability,
专注于可访问性、易用性，
and support security operations,
并支持安全操作，
and any other application or your scenario.
以及任何其他应用程序或您的使用场景。
But I think that most of these are the topic
但我认为这些大多数是主题
for this conference and
对于这次会议来说，
those panels to focus on.
这些面板是重点。
>> That's great, Beichuan.
>> 这太好了，北川。
Thanks. It's an impossible task to cover
谢谢。这是一个不可能完成的任务去覆盖
all of the codebase in such a short time.
所有的代码库在这么短的时间内。
But thank you for the noble effort.
但感谢你所做的高尚努力。
One very brief question for you to think,
一个让你思考的非常简短的问题，
to respond to you briefly, if you would.
为了简短回复你，如果可以的话。
A question came in about namespaces and
关于命名空间的一个问题进来了，
I'm wondering if anywhere
我想知道是否有任何地方
in the NDN codebase,
在NDN代码库中，
there is use of
在NDN代码库中，使用了标准的命名空间或
a standard namespace or
标准的命名空间或
naming conventions that have been
已经过NIST或其他机构标准化的命名规范。
standardized by NIST or others.
经NIST或其他机构标准化。
What's your reaction to that question?
你对那个问题有什么反应？
>> Any name convention
>> 命名规范？
being officially standardized?
是否被正式标准化？
>> Or any use of
>> 或任何使用
standardized naming conventions
标准化命名约定
in the NDN codebase.
在NDN代码库中。
>> I'm not aware of those cases.
>> 我不知道那些情况。
>> That's the answer I
>> 那就是我会给出的答案，
would have given as well,
我也会给出的。
that yours is the more authoritative one.
你的那个更具权威性。
Beichuan, thank you so much for
北川，非常感谢你……
covering so much in so little time.
在如此短的时间内涵盖了这么多内容。
We have a break right
我们现在有一个休息时间，对吧？
after this session and I certainly don't
在这个环节之后，我当然不会。
want to short-change
想要少付钱
our third and final speaker in the session.
我们这个环节的第三位也是最后一位演讲者。
Thank you, Beichuan.
谢谢你，北川。
Go ahead and stop sharing.
请停止分享。
Marcin Spoczynski from Intel
马尔辛·斯波琴斯基，来自英特尔公司。
is going to share with us
将与我们分享
his thoughts on developing practical
他关于开发实用的思考
end-to-end systems
端到端系统
and applications using NDN.
和使用NDN的应用程序。
Marcin, please take away.
马尔辛，请开始。
>> Can you see my screen?
>> 你能看到我的屏幕吗？
>> Yes, not yet in full-screen mode,
>> 是的，还没有全屏模式，
but we can see that you're sharing.
但我们可以看到你正在分享。
>> Is that full-screen mode or not?
>> 那是全屏模式吗？
No, it's not. Let me try once again.
不，不是。我再试一次。
Right now, it shows the right one.
现在它显示的是正确的一个。
I do believe I would be able to share.
我相信我应该能够分享。
Can you see the right screen?
你能看到右边的屏幕吗？
>> That's good. Yes, that's okay.
>> 那很好。是的，可以。
>> Thank you, Patrick. As Patrick said,
>> 谢谢你，帕特里克。正如帕特里克所说，
welcome to this third presentation.
欢迎来到第三场演讲。
My name is Marcin Spoczynski and I'm
我叫Marcin Spoczynski，我是
a Senior Research Scientist in Intel Labs.
我是英特尔实验室的一名高级研究科学家。
My background is in Cloud,
我的背景是在云计算领域，
edge orchestration enthusiast,
边缘编排爱好者，
contents system, and
内容系统，以及
application architecture.
应用程序架构。
My topic will be a little bit
我的话题会有一点儿不同
different and I will be talking
我的话题会有一点儿不同，我将会讨论
about developing
关于开发
those practical end-to-end system
这些实用的端到端系统
for NDN or with NDN.
为了NDN或者与NDN一起。
Before I will start,
在我开始之前，
I want to give a huge thanks to
我想要非常感谢
Kathyayani from Intel,
凯西亚妮，来自英特尔，
who helped me with this presentation.
帮助我完成这个演示的人。
Here is a sneak preview
这里有一个小预告
of what I will be talking.
我们将要探索我将要谈论的内容。
We are going to explore how
我们将要探索如何
are we using and build the NDN system,
我们将要探索如何使用并构建NDN系统，
not only in our lab,
不仅仅在我们的实验室里，
and challenges that we're facing.
和我们面临的挑战。
I will go from what do we mean by
我将从我们所说的什么是开始讲起
practical system and use
实用系统和使用
cases that our lab is looking,
我们实验室正在研究的案例，
and the practical system
涉及到实际系统。
components and end-to-end system.
组件和端到端系统。
Application and that best practices
应用和最佳实践
and the gaps that we see in an applicability.
以及我们在适用性中看到的差距。
Let me start with
让我从这里开始
those practical system requirements
那些实际的系统需求
that will define the needs for
将会定义需求
those system that we try to
我们尝试去实现的那些系统
implement and LM is
我们尝试去实现的那些系统，实施和LM是第三个定义套件。
the third defining kit
我们尝试去实现的那些系统，实施和LM是第三个定义套件，连同软件一起。
together with software.
连同软件一起。
At the very bottom,
在最底部，
what we really need
我们真正需要的
is this infrastructure layer,
是这个基础设施层，
which provides the complete storage network
它提供了完整的存储网络。
and the operating systems.
它还提供了操作系统。
Next, what we are
接下来，我们是
seeing the needs is this provisioning clear,
接下来，我们是看到需求，这种供应是否清晰，
which should consist of
它应该包括
those automation tools, for example,
那些自动化工具，例如，
a Chef, the Puppet,
和Chef、Puppet，
and Ansible to manage
和Ansible一起管理
the configuration environment together
与Ansible一起管理配置环境
with the application like
应用程序类似于~!@#$%^&*()
a SPHY maker that's helped
一家帮助过的SPHY制造商
the provisioning in the infrastructure.
在基础设施中的配置。
For example, managing the application images
例如，管理应用程序镜像
and deploying the application.
和部署应用程序。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
Another thing is the runtime that provides
另一个方面是提供的运行时环境。
the environment in which
提供的运行时环境。
your application runs,
您的应用程序运行的环境。
and it could be a container images where
和它可能是一个容器镜像，在哪里
orchestration runs along with
编排一同运行在
the associated storage and then networking.
关联的存储然后是网络。
The example could be
示例可能是
container D and our rootkit,
容器D和我们的根植工具，
and the other widely used
和另一个广泛使用的
in the container engines.
在容器引擎中。
The tools like the Kubernetes,
像Kubernetes这样的工具，在容器引擎中。Docker Swarm，摘要
Docker Swarm, abstract
Docker Swarm，摘要
the management application cluster,
管理应用程序集群，
along to schedule and orchestrate of
跨多个应用程序进行调度和编排
application across
跨应用程序
multiple published in the clusters.
在集群中多次发布。
Of course, we should able
当然，我们应该能够
to build the services and
构建服务和
the microservices for
构建微服务来
application across multiple languages.
应用程序跨多种语言。
For example, the Golang,
例如，Golang，
the Python, C++ or a Rust,
Python、C++或Rust，
to control vibes that
控制振动的
image management for application to
应用程序的图像管理
run across all of
跨越所有的
the infrastructure as container [inaudible].
基础设施作为容器[听不清]。
One of the key feature of
基础设施的一个关键特征是
those managing infrastructure is ability to
管理基础设施的能力包括监控和处理通信，
monitor and handle the communication,
监控和处理通信，
and underlying infrastructure.
和底层基础设施。
The last and I think the most important one
最后一个，我认为是最重要的一个
is about adopting in
是关于采纳在
a new paradigm requires
采纳新范式需要
a big cultural change where the teams,
一个重大的文化变革，在这种变革中，团队，
they can no longer work in
他们再也不能在这些独立的孤岛中工作
those independent silos just
他们再也不能在这些独立的孤岛中工作，just
to develop this small part of the system,
发展这个系统的这一小部分，
but this end-to-end automatization
但这种端到端的自动化
and the software delivery pipelines,
和软件交付管道，
it's just only possible
这仅仅是可能的
when there is the increase,
当出现增长时，
the collaboration between the researchers,
研究人员之间的合作，
the business partners, and the user.
我们把所有商业伙伴和用户都纳入考虑时，
When we put all of
our business partners and users into consideration, 当我们把所有商业伙伴和用户都纳入考虑时，
those pieces or we get this complete
我们得到这些零碎的部分，或者我们得到这个完整的。
end-to-end set up and suit it
端到端的设置和适配
for more people use cases.
为了适应更多人的使用场景。
But before that, let's talk a little
但在此之前，让我们稍微谈谈
bit about what we
我们稍微谈谈
think ideal system should look like.
我们稍微谈谈理想系统应该是什么样的。
The first, of course,
首先，当然是
the system must be simple.
系统必须简单。
Without a visible silo,
没有可见的筒仓，
allowing to distinct each of
允许区分每一个
the system command and then map
将系统命令然后映射
it to the one requirement and
将其映射到一个要求上，并且
the risk responsible for just only one job.
负责仅仅一个工作的风险。
The next point is to be generic enough
下一点是要足够通用，
to apply into the multiple scenarios,
应用于多种场景中，
to support different requirements
支持不同的需求
for each host and for example,
针对每个主机，例如，
for learning strategies or the caching.
针对学习策略或缓存。
Next following adaptive is
下一个适应性跟随是
to be at the scale to support
要有足够的规模来支持
heterogeneous architecture to be onboarded
异构架构以便进行整合
onto different kinds of
进入不同种类的
the hardware [inaudible].
[无法听清的内容]。
The Linux Windows or RISC-V and x86.
Linux、Windows 或 RISC-V 以及 x86。
Also, about all of
此外，关于所有的
the things that microsystems should
微系统应该支持的所有事物是完全可预测的行为。
support is a full predictable behavior
支持是一种完全可预测的行为。
to be a fully measure.
成为一种完全的衡量。
Even in those very dynamic scenarios,
即使在那些非常动态的场景中，
I should know what kind of
我应该知道什么类型的
the action the system
我应该知道什么类型的将采取的行动。
will take based on
将基于
the application logic or network traffic,
应用逻辑或网络流量，
which also depends on the use case.
这也取决于使用场景。
When talking about the use cases,
当谈到使用场景时，
I want to bring attention to two use cases,
我想强调两个使用案例，
which we support on
我们支持的
our lab development process.
我们的实验室开发流程。
The first is the industrial IoT
首先是工业物联网
when the new application requires
当新应用程序需要
the high flexibility from
高度灵活性来自
the network to allow
网络允许
assembly services on
提供组装服务
the fly and autonomously,
自主飞行，
reconfigure the network interfaces,
重新配置网络接口，
allowing not only to
允许不仅可以
support best network software,
支持最佳网络软件，
but also to bring support for
但也为了带来支持
the deterministic Ethernet and WiFi to enable
确定性以太网和WiFi以实现
right on time delivery for
及时交付
sensory data and application
感测数据和应用
required for a software PLC.
需要用于软件PLC。
We see the big trends in
我们看到了大趋势在
the direction of the full network autonomy in
我们看到了大趋势在全网自主性的方向发展, those industrial application started with ~!@#$%^&*()
those industrial application started with
这些工业应用起始于~!@#$%^&*()
Industry 4.0 and the softwarization
工业4.0和软件化
of the factory floor applications.
工厂车间应用。
The second use case is the gaming,
第二个用例是游戏领域，
where we are looking at
我们正在查看
the two application modes.
我们正在查看两种应用模式。
The first is the WebRTC and
第一个是WebRTC和
dynamic flooding of the compute functions
计算功能的动态泛滥
and distributed rendering,
和分布式渲染，
where each of the gaming frames
与分布式渲染相关的场景部分
can be disassembled and processed separately.
可以拆分独立处理。
We're seeing a lot of
我们正在看到很多~!@#$%^&*()
opportunities in both case in the end.
在最后，两种情况都存在机会。
Let's see the system and
让我们来看看这个系统并且
vision and deploy it on our testbed,
让我们来看看这个系统并且在我们的测试平台上部署它，
which can enable this end-to-end platform
可以使这个端到端平台实现
before they're presented before use cases.
在它们被用于用例之前。
Let's start from application layer.
让我们从应用层开始。
When we are supporting
当我们在支持
multiple different application
多种不同的应用程序
as from industrial control,
从工业控制，
which are the software program,
这些是软件程序，
programmable logic controller,
可编程逻辑控制器，
in short the vPLCs
简而言之，这些可编程逻辑控制器
with NDN support together in
with NDN (Named Data Networking) support together in
par with the sensors that can expose
与能够暴露的传感器并驾齐驱
collected data on our distributed clusters.
收集了我们分布式集群上的数据。
Setup of gaming use case,
游戏用例的设置，
we use the Pion WebRTC [inaudible]
我们使用Pion WebRTC [无法听清]
with enabling NDN support.
启用了NDN支持。
We also enabled tracing
我们还启用了跟踪功能。
in the telemetry support using
在遥测支持使用中
the IP services to fully
充分利用IP服务来
understand the footprint of
理解足迹分布情况
the mentioned applications,
提到的应用程序，
to be able to compare
能够进行比较
the same applications with their IP versions.
相同的应用程序及其IP版本。
I love those applications,
我喜欢那些应用程序，
I deploy the Kubernetes interface
我部署了Kubernetes接口。
with the outlook
展望未来
of the function to well know
了解该功能的情况
DPDK and the SPDK APIs.
DPDK和SPDK的API。
Additionally, in case
此外，如果情况是这样的话，
of industrial application,
工业应用领域，
traffic and some of
交通和一些
the management function can use
管理功能可以使用
this OPC UA plan
这个OPC UA方案
going down to the network layer,
下探至网络层，
through those CNI plugins,
通过这些CNI插件，
and the different types of NFDs,
以及不同类型的NFDs，
we are able to onboard framework to
我们能够将框架集成到
those Kubernetes on the Edge type of
我们能够将框架集成到那些在边缘类型的Kubernetes上，
the devices and
我们能够将框架集成到那些在边缘类型的Kubernetes上，设备和高性能服务器内部。
the high power within servers.
服务器内部的高性能。
What is on the next screen
~!@#$%^&*()
is where we'll see how
是我们将看到如何
specific software can be used in
特定软件可以用于
the case of the
在典型的工业控制场景中
typical industrial control scenario,
在典型的工业控制场景中，
where factory control level
在典型的工业控制场景中，工厂控制层支持不同的使用案例。
support and different use cases
支持并适用于不同的使用案例。
and the usage models.
和使用模型。
For example, typical in
例如，典型的在使用模型的工业场景中，
an industrial scenario,
一个工业场景，
we'll see this factory cloud where
我们将会看到这个工厂的云端，
the most of the analytics happen,
我们将会看到这个工厂的云端，大部分的分析工作会发生在这里，并且是由
and is powered by
和由...提供动力
high-end servers uploaded by
高端服务器上传的
the user interface framework like
类似于用户界面框架
DPDK or SPDK and etc.
DPDK或SPDK等。
But due to low power and
但由于功耗低和
the typical Edge devices running
典型的边缘设备运行
on the item and the typical,
项目上和典型的，
maybe i7, i5 chips we are using
也许我们正在使用的是i7、i5处理器
yet another NFD together
但又有一个新的NFD一起出现了。
with the virus and network supports.
伴随着病毒和网络支持。
Also worth mention in existing scenario,
在现有情况下也值得一提的是，
we're still using typical
我们仍在使用典型的
this style of building,
这种风格的建筑，
where the factory Cloud is handling
工厂云正在处理
most of those orchestration functions.
大多数的编排功能。
But in the enablement of OPC UA plane,
但在启用OPC UA平面方面，
we hope to enable
我们希望能够启用
the fully distributed way
全分布式的方式
of managing resources,
管理资源的方式，
application and the hardware resources.
应用程序和硬件资源。
Let's zoom into application for
让我们放大看一下应用程序的
a moment to show how we
我们花一点时间来展示我们如何
actually develop application for
实际上为了开发应用程序，我们花一点时间来展示我们如何使用我们的测试平台来启用
our testbed to enable
我们的测试平台来启用
those use cases together
将这些用例结合起来
with this practical scenario.
将这些用例结合起来，与这个实际情景一起，在呈现之前，申请。
Before presented, application
在呈现之前，申请。
should be a drivers of the NDN and
应该是NDN的驱动因素，
those caching policies and how we are
那些缓存策略以及我们如何
forwarding the data highly
将数据高效地转发
depends on the business
取决于业务需求
needs and application.
取决于业务需求和应用。
For the most of the code,
对于大部分代码来说，
we are using those Golang and the
我们正在使用那些Golang和...
Rust for most advanced application,
用于最先进应用的Rust,
and the automation code form
和自动化代码形式
a previous slide is brought under Python.
之前的幻灯片已经用Python处理。
We developed share of
我们开发了份额的
the application to enable
我们开发了份额的应用程序以启用它提到的用例
it mention use cases
它提到了用例
like a software PLC
像一个软件PLC
together with the NDN support,
与NDN支持一起，
are also the sensory data applications that
也是感官数据应用程序，它们
can gather and accumulate sensory data.
可以收集和积累感官数据。
For the gaming, we mentioned before,
对于我们之前提到的游戏，
the Pion WebRTC Golang
Pion WebRTC Golang
with a partial NDN support,
具有部分NDN支持，
and we are planning to fully put it into NDN.
我们计划将其完全整合进NDN中。
On the integration side for
我们计划将其完全整合进
our testbed we provide full integration of
我们计划将其完全整合进我们的测试环境中，以提供完整的集成。
the NFD with Kubernetes
我们计划将其完全整合进我们的测试环境中，以提供完整的集成，因此它被部署为一个服务在NFD与Kubernetes中。
so it's deployed as a service in
我们因此将其部署为一个服务在
the case of the NDN and
我们因此将其部署为一个服务在NDN的情况下，或者也可以与另一个NAD一起使用。
DPDK or also with yet another NAD.
我们因此可以将其与DPDK一起部署，或者甚至可以与另一个NAD一起使用。
As one of our goals is to have
我们的目标之一是要有
the applicability to deploy
应用部署的适用性
application in IP and NDN,
应用在IP和NDN中，
let's look a little bit how actually we
让我们稍微看一下实际上我们是如何
develop application to be
开发应用程序以便
used on our testbed.
用于我们的测试平台。
For that, we develop a small framework
为此，我们开发了一个小型框架
when we divide the application
当我们划分应用程序时
in mostly four layers.
通常分为四层。
The first layer that
通常分为四层。第一层是指
handles the logic for application,
处理应用程序的逻辑，
the mostly code specific for
处理应用程序的逻辑，大多是特定于程序的代码，和可编程逻辑控制器以及
programmable logic controllers and
可编程逻辑控制器和
the PLC, video and analytics.
可编程逻辑控制器、视频和分析。
The second is a protocol
第二个是一个协议
translation libraries.
翻译库。
As some of the libraries,
作为其中一些库，
we need to have that layers in
我们需要有那些层在
the specific protocol is
我们需要有那些层在，特定的协议是，not supported by application.
not supported by application.
不受应用程序支持。
Next is the Data Mapper,
下一个是数据映射器，
when we are mapping those address spaces
当我们在映射那些地址空间时
from NDN to other formats like for example,
从NDN到其他格式，例如，
mDNS and so on or at the consul.
mDNS等或在consul上。
This model is at this moment
这个模型目前处于
we are looking at
我们正在查看
is theoretically hardcoded,
理论上是硬编码的，
but we would love to see
但我们很希望看到
the library like that,
能即时翻译的图书馆
which can translate on the fly
能即时翻译
dynamic DNS space to the NDN namespace.
将动态DNS空间映射到NDN命名空间。
Another one is network
另一个是网络。
specific code though the NDN,
通过NDN发送特定代码，
TCP or the Modbus
TCP或Modbus
in case of the industrial application,
在工业应用场景中，
where we are able to plug in and
我们能够插入并且
integrate with a specific network libraries.
我们能够插入并且与特定的网络库集成。
This framework let us think
这个框架让我们思考
about the software rather than how
关于软件本身而非如何
to apply
应用
specific network techniques to the use case.
特定网络技术应用于用例。
We're assuming as end-to-end system
我们假设一个端到端的系统。
that we have is not
我们拥有的并不是
definitely what we're imaging.
绝对不是我们所想象的。
The majority of the many components
大多数的众多组件
is still far from perfect,
仍然远非完美，
but we see a lot of the gaps that we
但我们看到很多我们所存在的差距，
will allow to see the address there.
将允许看到那里的地址。
The first is this migration framework,
这是第一个迁移框架，
which without given
无法给出的哪一个
the specific the business logic,
特定的业务逻辑，
translate easy plugin and the libraries,
翻译简易插件和库，
a preference label it with the software for
为软件添加一个偏好标签。
languages goes
语言发展
more modern languages like rust,
更现代的语言，如Rust，
or even more matter of support for a golang,
或者甚至更多地支持Golang，
that we already have.
我们已经拥有的。
Additionally, we would like to see how
此外，我们还想看看如何
specific those TCP problems can
特定的那些TCP问题能够
be addressed at the end of the year while
在年底时得到解决，同时使用像WebRTC和TCP这样的协议。
using the protocols like WebRTC and TCP.
使用像WebRTC和TCP这样的协议。
One of the things is asked, enabling.
Using protocols like WebRTC and TCP. Integration and automation of enabling.
Integration and automation of
集成和自动化
deployment connected with integration
部署与集成相连
through this Kubernetes network logins.
通过这个Kubernetes网络登录。
The other way where
另一种方式在哪里
the most popular orchestrators
最受欢迎的编排器
would be very beneficial.
将会非常有益。
Additionally, enhancement of
此外，增强
existing multiverse of the support
现有的多元宇宙的支持
for make it the before the distributed.
为了使其在分布之前制作好。
It can be updated from any point of
它可以从任何点进行更新，以便在分布之前制作好，以完全分布的方式在网络中。
the network in a fully distributed way.
它以完全分布的方式在网络中。
Even when one of the node with the offline
即使其中一个节点离线
or you'd have a time
或者你会有一段时间
down will be huge, caching.
下行将会有巨大的缓存。
To conclude, NDN developers
为了总结，NDN开发者
did a really tremendous job in the creating
在创建过程中做了非常了不起的工作
this NDN DPDK and yet have
~!@#$%^&*()
the and other great pieces
的和其他伟大作品
of the software and architecture.
的软件和架构。
What is still lots of
~!@#$%^&*()
opportunities in this NDN?
机遇在这个NDN中？
However, as we understand that
然而，正如我们所理解的那样
API will be still used by the long time.
API 仍将被长期使用。
We need this, the backward possibility
我们需要这个，向后兼容的可能性。
of the portability,
的可移植性，
and the PowerShell compatibility.
和PowerShell的兼容性。
It goes to all projects to
它适用于所有项目以
be easily integrated
可以轻松集成
into software frameworks.
集成到软件框架中。
We see a lot of the needs of
我们看到了很多需求
our standardization of the API
我们对API的标准化
that are facing the user as
面向用户的
a fragmentation of the software.
软件的碎片化。
It's a big deal.
这是件大事。
We like to see different approaches,
我们喜欢看到不同的方法，
but we do believe that's the interface facing
但我们确实相信面向开发者和用户的界面应该是一致的。
developers and the user should be the same.
开发者和用户应该是一致的。
Another point is
另一个观点是
where we see a lot of opportunity of
我们看到了很多机会在~!@#$%^&*()
offloading storage network and the compute
卸载存储网络和计算资源
to be competitive with
要与...竞争
the other network paradigms.
要与其他网络范式竞争。
We have the start with DPDK and the SPDK.
我们已经开始使用DPDK和SPDK。
However, we like to
然而，我们喜欢
see the more modern approaches
看到更现代的方法
SBRT related to the Linux kernel
SBRT 与 Linux 内核相关
and the extension for that.
以及对此的扩展。
Last but not least,
最后但同样重要的是，
is really understanding the developers who
最后但同样重要的是，真正理解开发者们的需求，他们的需求实际上来自不同的地方。
comes really from different places
实际上来自不同的地方
with different needs.
有着不同的需求。
When developing the software,
在开发软件时，我们需要深入思考它们。
we need to think a lot about them.
我们需要深入思考它们。
I think that is my last slide.
我认为那是我的最后一张幻灯片。
I don't know how much time we have, but.
我不知道我们有多少时间，但是。
>> Thank you, Marcin,
谢谢你，Marcin。
we have a minute or two for questions.
我们有一两分钟时间提问。
You did a good job staying on target.
你做得很好，保持了目标不偏离。
One question that came in through Slack.
一个通过Slack提出的问题。
Specifically here at the end,
具体来说，在最后这里，
you raised some issues
你提出了一些问题
that require further work.
需要进一步处理的。
think are especially important
认为特别重要的
for the research community as
对研究社区来说同样重要的
opposed to commercial participants?
反对商业参与者吗？
Is there one or two that you
你认为有一个或两个你最...
think would be most
我认为将会是最~!@#$%^&*()
relevant for the research
对研究具有相关性
community to act on?
社区采取行动？
>> I do believe that one of
我确信其中一个
the very important things
非常重要的事情
about this integration and
关于这个集成和~!@#$%^&*()
the stabilization of the API.
API的稳定性。
It will give the great opportunity
它将提供巨大的机会
for developers to try on.
为开发者尝试的机会。
Especially that's a lot of
尤其是那真是很多
those edge developers who just
那些刚刚开始熟悉边缘计算框架的开发者
coming up to speed with the edge framework.
正在开始熟悉边缘计算框架。
If the NDN will be the one of
如果NDN将成为其中一种
the new possible way
那么新的可能方式
of developing applications,
的开发应用程序，
definitely that will gather
肯定会聚集~!@#$%^&*()
a lot of the interests of those developer.
这些开发者的许多利益。
We see lots of opportunities,
我们看到了很多机会，
especially from our business units.
尤其是来自我们的业务部门。
>> I think I'm tracking that.
>> 我觉得我明白了。
There's a further question
关于NDN传输的进一步问题
about the NDN transport
关于NDN传输
for these apps you've described.
您所描述的这些应用程序。
Are you typically replacing
您通常是在替换
HTTP or TCP with NDN?
HTTP或TCP与NDN相比如何？
>> I'm typically replacing
我通常是在替换
TCP at this moment.
在这个时刻的TCP。
In some of the cases, for example,
在某些情况下，例如，
in the OPC away,
在OPC离开的情况下，
we are replacing the TCP and HTTP.
我们正在替换TCP和HTTP。
It depends on the use case.
它取决于使用场景。
I think we need to, in this case,
我认为在这种情况下，我们需要
we need to be fragmented because each of
我们需要碎片化处理，因为每一个
the use case and application
我们需要碎片化处理，因为每一个使用案例和应用场景will require different,
will require different,
approaches, strategies, or technologies, and especially that we need to be
and especially that we need to be
与一些现有的标准保持一致。
in line with some of the existing standards.
符合一些现有的标准。
So the search for
So the search for ~!@#$%^&*()
a passport is really beneficial.
护照确实很有用。
>> Great.
>> 很好。
Well, the questions are starting to fly
好吧，问题开始纷飞了。
into the Slack chat room now,
进入Slack聊天室吧。
which is our break time now.
现在是我们的休息时间。
But obviously, we all have a lot more time
但显然，我们都有更多的时间
to ask questions and respond to
提出问题并回应
those questions in the Slack chat rooms.
那些在Slack聊天室中的问题。
These do continue the conversation
这些确实延续了对话
there as I hope you've seen
那里，我希望你已经看到了
Qian Shao in
Before the dawn
this web conferencing chat window
这个网络会议聊天窗口
posted the link to join the Slack chat room.
已经发布了加入Slack聊天室的链接。
If you've not done so, please do that.
如果你还没有这样做，请去做。
Marci, thank you very much
Marci，非常感谢你
for a very interesting and.
为一个非常有趣和。
Thank you, Patrick.
谢谢你，帕特里克。
Presentation. I had several questions
陈述。我有几个问题。
I was going to ask myself,
我本来打算问自己，
but unfortunately, I didn't get to ask any
但不幸的是，我一个问题也没能问出来。
because there are some interesting points
因为有一些有趣的观点。
file in here too.
将文件也放在这里。
With that, we will now commence our break.
那么，我们现在开始休息。
We'll have a 10-minute break.
我们将休息10分钟。
We will resume at
我们将在稍后继续。
15 minutes after the hour
时针过了整点15分钟
for the second session,
对于第二个环节，
which is focused on application development,
专注于应用程序开发，
which is a perfectly appropriate follow-up
这是一个非常合适的后续讨论内容。
to this conversation
这是一个非常合适的后续讨论内容，因为许多这些命名空间的话题，对于这次对话来说是一个很好的延续。
because many of these topics of namespaces,
因为许多这些命名空间的话题，
naming choices,
命名选择，
and architectural tradeoffs,
和架构上的权衡，
and broader adoption will
和更广泛的采用将会
be considered in that session as well.
也将在那个会议中考虑。
Lofti, is there anything
Lofti，还有什么
else you wanted to add?
你还有什么想要补充的吗？
I see you've turned on the video.
我看到你已经打开了视频。
>> No, that's it. We have a 10-minute break.
不，就这样。我们有10分钟的休息时间。
We'll be back at 11:15.
我们将在11点15分回来。
Thank you very much, Patrick.
非常感谢你，帕特里克。
>> Okay.
好的。
>> You're all leaving. Thanks.
>> 你们都要走了。谢谢。